Dave Kavanagh

Address: 135 Carton Wood, Maynooth, Kildare LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dave-kavanagh/Email: dave.kavanagh87@gmail.com

Tel: 083 427 4918

PROFILE

Motivated, enthusiastic & personable Software Engineer, with a thirst for knowledge and passion for problem-solving. Proven ability to integrate well with a team, as well as to work under own initiative. Backend Typescript/Java/Scala developer with experience in a range of other languages and technologies in backend, frontend, and DevOps disciplines.

Key Skills

- Typescript, JavaScript, NodeJS
- Scala, Java, Spring
- · Build tools, Bash Scripting

- IntelliJ, VsCode, Git, Jenkins
- API design
- Experience in leading teams/projects

CAREER HISTORY

Apata, Senior Software Engineer

2022 - Present

- Working with the Strong Customer Authentication/3DSecure domain, building the next generation ACS to provide flexible and secure authentication solutions for eCommerce transactions in a fast-paced startup environment.
- Leading design and development of key new features and services in TypesScript, JavaScript, AWS.
- Lead migration of codebase from JavaScript to TypeScript

Salesforce, Software Engineer

2021 - 2022

- Worked as part of the Salesforce on Slack team, integrating Salesforce functionality, creating slack apps in TypeScript and back end integrations in Java/Spring.
- Additionally working with AWS, Jenkins, Terraform.

Workday, Software Engineer - Distributed Systems

2017 - 2021

- Scala/Java Developer, working on both legacy code and in green field projects.
- Initially working in both a back-end and front-end capacity, with additional CI/CD build responsibilities. Primarily leaning into backend development ultimately.
- Maintenance of legacy the integration runtime platform improving the reliability of the service, troubleshooting and diagnosing Production Support issues and contributing to the foundation of the next generation of the Integration Runtime.
- Working in a highly distributed micro service oriented architecture based around Scala and Java with high complexity in terms of interdependent modules and services.
- Extra curricular actives including leading a team of fellow engineers to produce a curriculum of onboarding materials for incoming engineers to expedite their learning of the Scala programming language.

Qumas/Dassault Systémes, Software Development Intern

2016 - 2016

- Research and Development placement as part of college curriculum.
- Prototyping PoC for data ingestion and indexing for proprietary search engine via both push and pull APIs.
- Worked with real time data stream processing technologies such as Apache Spark and Kafka

EDUCATION

BSc. Software Development, Cork Institute of Technology

2013 - 2017

Grade: First class honours

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

- I'll browse the likes of HackerNews and ProductHunt daily, I like to keep in touch with new tools and trends.
- ' I'm a huge sports fan and love to watch Football, Rugby, Golf, Boxing, MMA, Formula 1, Comedy.
- I completed my first marathon in Dublin '22, hopeful of completing my second next year after a hiatus this year.